<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<component type="desktop-application">
  <id>com.deathpush.app</id>
  <metadata_license>CC0-1.0</metadata_license>
  <project_license>Apache-2.0</project_license>
  <name>DeathPush</name>
  <summary>A standalone desktop Git client with the VS Code Source Control UX</summary>

  <description>
    <p>
      DeathPush is a standalone desktop Git client that replicates the VS Code
      Source Control UX. Beautiful diffs powered by Monaco Editor, clean staging,
      branch management, integrated terminal, and zero bloat. Built with Tauri
      and Rust for native performance.
    </p>
    <p>Features:</p>
    <ul>
      <li>VS Code Source Control UX -- familiar staging workflow with inline diff toggles, file-level staging, and chunk-level control</li>
      <li>Monaco-powered diffs -- full Monaco editor for diffs with syntax highlighting, inline editing, and side-by-side or unified views</li>
      <li>Branch management -- create, switch, merge, rebase, rename, and delete branches with full remote tracking</li>
      <li>Image diffs -- visual comparison for image changes with side-by-side, overlay, and difference modes</li>
      <li>Git blame and file history -- line-by-line blame annotations with full file history timeline</li>
      <li>Integrated terminal -- built-in terminal with PTY support for running git commands and scripts</li>
      <li>Stash, tags, and cherry-pick -- full stash management, tag creation, and cherry-pick support</li>
      <li>Multi-window -- open multiple repositories in separate windows, each with its own state</li>
      <li>Theme support -- multiple built-in themes including dark, light, and high-contrast variants</li>
      <li>Built with Rust -- Tauri + Rust backend for native performance, fast startup, and low memory usage</li>
    </ul>
  </description>

  <launchable type="desktop-id">deathpush.desktop</launchable>

  <url type="homepage">https://deathpush.com</url>
  <url type="bugtracker">https://github.com/felipefdl/deathpush/issues</url>
  <url type="vcs-browser">https://github.com/felipefdl/deathpush</url>

  <screenshots>
    <screenshot type="default">
      <caption>Main view with staged and unstaged changes and side-by-side diff</caption>
      <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/felipefdl/deathpush/main/assets/screenshots/main.png</image>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <caption>Branch management with merge and rebase support</caption>
      <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/felipefdl/deathpush/main/assets/screenshots/branches.png</image>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <caption>Integrated terminal with PTY support</caption>
      <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/felipefdl/deathpush/main/assets/screenshots/terminal.png</image>
    </screenshot>
  </screenshots>

  <categories>
    <category>Development</category>
    <category>Utility</category>
    <category>RevisionControl</category>
  </categories>

  <provides>
    <binary>deathpush</binary>
    <binary>dp</binary>
  </provides>

  <releases>
    <release version="0.1.2" date="2025-06-01">
      <description>
        <p>Fix download links and improve distribution packaging.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.1.1" date="2025-05-30">
      <description>
        <p>Fix favicon, Open Graph metadata, and add SVG assets.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.1.0" date="2025-05-28">
      <description>
        <p>Initial release of DeathPush with VS Code Source Control UX, Monaco-powered diffs, branch management, integrated terminal, and more.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
  </releases>

  <content_rating type="oars-1.1" />

  <developer id="com.ferreiradelima">
    <name>Felipe Lima</name>
  </developer>
</component>
